it's like the most severe spinal
cord injury you can have
when they told me I was paralyzed
I told them that I wasn't paralyzed
so  my son was in Canada
and he was playing a hockey
game in a hockey tournament
he caught an edge
and he threw
he flew like face first into the boards
there happened to be a firefighter
that was there that was able to incubate him
because he did not breathe for like eight minutes
Saturday morning
probably at like 3:00am
his accident was at 10 o'clock at night
um
a neurosurgeon went in and they fused his C1 and C2
which is at the top of your spinal cord
so it would be like right next to your brainstem
he had no feeling and he was
considered a complete severe injury
so they said there was no hope of recovery
so like I had asked the doctors
you know the chances like one in 10
they said absolutely not
and at this point
he is vent dependent
feeding tube dependent
we're told he's never gonna eat or drink
or be able to breathe independently
I had a friend and she's like hey
I know of this thing that's supposed
to help spinal cord injuries
and it helps reduce the swallowing
and I'm like OK
well  maybe we can try that
because at this point
we didn't have any options
when you have an injury this severe
you're basically like people are sending me
Neuralink things to like put a brain chip in
we decided to try it topically
we bought like a little rollerball one
and I would just rub it on his skin because
it kind of looks like a lotion ball
nobody thought anything of it
I was just rubbing this DMSO on his body
we started that on day 4 or 5
and by day seven
I would poke his feet or his legs
and he would open his eyes
cause they have him on like propofol  um
fat now whatever kinds of drugs they put you on
it's a lot of drugs  so
he's pretty out of it  I mean
he was in ICU for 21 days there  and I think
he thought it was three days  so
but I would start poking him
and he would wake up
or he would respond to me poking his legs and arms
he was probably a complete injury for
probably 21 to 24 days
it wasn't until we made it to the step down
ICU that he became an incomplete injury  and then
there was a PT working with him and
she felt his hip flexor fire
and they're like oh my gosh
he went from an Asia a to an Asia C
which usually is not supposed to happen
you're either a severe spinal
cord injury with no sensation  nothing
like an Asia A
you don't go from an a to a C  from there
he was A's and C's
and I'm still rubbing this stuff
on him every chance I get  I mean
I would rub that thing on him probably 10 times a day
what's interesting is I was able to rub it on his
left side of his body more than his right side
his left side is definitely stronger
on the right is the way his ventilator
was for probably the first 6 months
so when he was hooked up to the ventilator
I couldn't actually get the DMSO on the right side
we're still using it
the right side is slowly coming back
his hand grip on this side was like one pound
probably four months ago
and now it's up to 20 pounds
he literally has every single like fine motor skill
it's a matter of us now strengthening that
he is 16 months out from his injury
and he hasn't used his wheelchair in three weeks
now in October
I think the end of October
he took his first steps
and it was with like a big
Argo walker
and then like in November
we move to a platform walker
January or February
February we move to like a normal walker
and then just in
may we move to the arm crutches and now in therapy
he's working on walking without the arm crutches
we were like ventilator dependent
medication dependent
my son's off of most of his
medications before he was probably on like
50 or 60 medications and now we're
down to just the back of it
my son is one of the only people I've met that
does not have the nerve pain with his condition
so he is off of all nerve pain meds
there's no money to be made off of it if you
have a bunch of walking quadriplegics that
are self sufficient running around